你不是才给他剪过头发吗
Didn't you just cut his hair?
对 但今天是他的幼儿园毕业派对
Yes, but it's his kindergarten graduation party today.
好了 告别不要搂搂抱抱 我走了
Okay, no messy goodbyes, I'm out of here.
宝贝 我会想死你的
Ay, papi, I'm going to miss you.
你能不能至少留下来参加我为乔办的派对
Can you at least stay for the party that I'm making for Joe?
妈妈 努斯鲍姆太太花钱雇我
Mom, Mrs. Nussbaum is paying me
在周五中午前帮她把车开到特拉华州
to get her car to Delaware by Friday at noon.
我已经浪费了一小时找我的驾驶手套
I already lost an hour looking for my driving gloves.
你要开着辆毛毛虫绿的丰田凯美瑞
You're plowing through the heartlands
穿过民风剽悍的中部
in an inchworm-green Camry
车尾贴还写着"吃肉等同谋杀"
with a bumper sticker that says "Meat is Murder."
我是故意把这副手套藏起来的
I hid these gloves for a reason.
听着 叫你当心点可不是玩笑话
Listen, uh, we weren't kidding about you being careful.
不是我夸张 记得要提高警惕
And, uh, not to get dramatic, just keep your wits about you.
给
Here.
这是什么鬼
What the hell is that?
还能是空气清新剂吗 你说是什么
It's an air freshener. What does it look like?
我是要去玛莎·斯图尔特的
I'm going on the Martha Stewart
美国民宿之旅
bed-and-breakfast tour of America,
又不是探索男子气概土著之旅
not an Aboriginal manhood quest.
我没说你会用得到
I'm not saying you're gonna need it,
只是有备无患
just better safe than sorry.
划就行 千万别用捅的
Slash, don't stab.
别动来动去 我快好啦
Stop wiggling. I'm almost done.
你干嘛倒抽一口气
Why'd you gasp?
不要 头发是我的身份象征啊
Ah! My hair is my identity!
小卡 看来我还是得干个活
Uh, Cam? Uh, turns out I have to do that work thing after all.
我们在乔的派对上见好吗
I'll meet you at Joe's party?
好的 卡尔 过来抱抱你米奇尔舅舅
Oh, okay. Cal, come give your Uncle Mitchell a hug.
抱抱
Hug!
不 不要抱抱 他人呢
No. No, no hug. No -- where is he?
他从哪个方向跑来 哪个方向
Which way is he coming from? Coming from?
小卡姐姐的儿子现在暂住我们家
Cam's sister's son is staying with us
因为 你们懂的 她又被关进监狱了
because, well, you know, she's back in jail.
但她没做什么大坏事
But she didn't do anything terrible.
她只是不明白
She just didn't understand
她上次坐牢的假释条款 她...
the rules of her probation from last time, when --
她上次做了一些小坏事
When she did something a little terrible.
但我们准备把小卡尔
But we're taking baby Cal back to
送回农场跟我父母住
live with my parents on the farm.
这是好事 因为他并不是...
Which is a good thing because he's not really a --
适合家养的宝宝
a house baby.
真不是 他力气大得惊人 块头大到破表
No, no, he's freakishly strong and off the charts size-wise.
没有破表啦 数一数二而已啦
On the charts. 99th percentile.
他只有两颗牙 但我见过他吃掉整只鸡
He has two teeth and I've seen him eat a whole chicken.
好了 我得走了
All right, I got to go.
等等 给我的抱抱呢
Wait, where's my hug?
-抱抱 -走 快走 快逃命
- Hug! - Go! Go! Save yourself!
我们的戏服在后座
Our costumes are in the back.
菲尔和我要去参加英雄展
Phil and I are going to Hero-Con
放纵我们对奇幻小说的热爱
to indulge in our love of fantasy fiction.
我一直都很想去
Um, I-I've always wanted to go,
但这个展会偏宅男向
but I-it's a little nerd-forward,
我以前总担心我家人会取笑我
and I was always afraid my family would make fun of me.
所以我叫菲尔保守这个秘密
So I've asked Phil to keep it between us.
所以我们选了秘密的战士暗号
That's why we chose our secret warrior signal.
我第一个提议是吹维京号角
My first suggestion was to blow a Viking horn.
-对了 千万别上网搜 -已经搜了
- Don't ever Google that, by the way. - I already did.
今年 我们最喜欢的剧要办见面座谈会
This year, there's a panel, um, on our favorite show,
《神剑之战》
"Clash of Swords."
这剧含有大量暴力情节和女性裸体
It's got a lot of graphic violence and female nudity,
但那也正合每个男人体内的
but that's part of its appeal
勇猛战士的胃口
to the fierce warrior inside every man.
我的眼线一直晕开
My eyeliner keeps smudging.
真是"谢谢"你的推荐啊 彩妆专柜柜姐
Thanks a lot, gal at the MAC counter.
管他呢 我们看起来帅极了
Who cares? We look great.
我们上吧
Let's do this!
要记得我们把可靠的坐骑停在了22B
Just remember we left our trusty steed in section 22B.
我做不到 菲尔
I can't do it, Phil.
好吧 我可以写下来
Oh, okay. I can write it down.
不不 我以为我准备好了 但其实没有
No, no. I-I-I thought I was ready, but I'm not.
我没准备好 我幻想了要来这么久
I'm not. I-I've fantasized so long about coming,
现在我们真的来了 我却
and now that -- that we're here, I am...
我却感到羞愧 我都是40岁的老男人了
I'm mortified, okay? I'm a 40-year-old man.
你才不是
No, you're not.
你是个390岁的高地北境人
You're a 390-year-old Highland Norph.
跟着一名职业勇士入场
And you're walking in with a lifer.
这宝贝能让我们畅行无阻 还送两杯蜂蜜酒
This baby gets us all-access and two free yards of mead.
你的命运就在那些门背后
Through those doors lies your destiny.
"勇敢"用盖尔德语怎么说
What's the Galderean word for "Bravery"?
辣个汤尼
Lochtani.
-再说一遍 -辣个汤尼
- Again! - Lochtani.
嘛哩嘛哩哄
Namu oponggi su-whi-gorth!
你有看到玛格丽特吗
Have you seen Margaret?
我要她把我今天的日程排开
I need her to clear my day.
我刚发现可以在网上收看高尔夫频道
I just found out you can get the Golf Channel online.
没有 她又请病假了
Nope, she's out sick again.
爸爸 别忘了我们要跟
Oh, Dad, don't forget we're about to meet with
那所新企业的人见面
those guys from that start-up.
对哦 一群有抱负的衣柜界新丁
Oh, right, aspiring closeteers
想向行业传奇寻求建议
seeking advice from an industry legend.
是的 记得要跳过那一段
Yeah, just skip that part of your speech
就是你说"不是我选择了衣柜..."
where you say "I didn't choose closets --"
是衣柜选择了我
They chose me!
我们不知道该把羽绒背心挂在哪儿
...We didn't know where to hang up our puffer vests,
于是就随便丢在某人桌上了
so we just dropped them on some rando's desk.
你好 你们就是伊瑟拉视界的人吧
Hi. You must be the guys from EzraVision.
没错 我是尼克 这些是我的员工
Yes, I am Nick. And these are my guys.
不用说 我就是杰·普里契特
Jay Pritchett, obviously.
各位请坐 不要拘束
Fellas, take a seat. Make yourself comfortable.
哪一位负责拿录音机记录
Which one is gonna be holding the tape recorder?
这样吧 不如我们速战速决
You know what? Why don't we just make this quick?
我们等下还得去车行逛逛
We actually have to go hang out in a bike shop
那里只放嘻哈歌手德雷克的歌
that only plays Drake.
这是我们最终的最高报价
So here's our offer, best and final.
什么报价
Offer for what?
买下你们公司的报价
For your company.
我们想买下你们
We want to buy you out.
不好意思 我们以为你们只是来
I'm sorry, we thought that you were here to just,
搜集信息
you know, get information.
给我滚出去
Get out of here!
爸爸 不如让我来沟通吧
Dad, if you would just let me speak --
你以为自己是谁
Who do you think you are,
大步走进来自以为是一群大老板
marching in here like a bunch of hotshots?
为什么没人穿袜子
And why is nobody wearing socks?!
血压别这么高 老人家
Ooh, lower the B.P., O.G.
我们其实算是在帮你们一个大忙
We're actually trying to do you a favor.
我认为是你们没搞清楚
Okay, I think you have this twisted.
这间公司在你们所有人出生前就成立了
This company has been around since before you all were born.
或许除了他 他是怎么回事
Except for maybe him. How is he part of this?
这家伙吗 为了显得年龄多样化雇的
This guy? That's our over-40 diversity hire.
我们已经开发出了智能衣柜技术
Listen, we have developed smart-closet technology
你们这种公司迟早会被淘汰
that's gonna make places like this obsolete.
我们是给你们机会
We are giving you a chance
在还有优势时全身而退
to get out while you're still ahead.
说到全身而退 给我滚出去
Speaking of which -- Get out of here!
那好 我的出价48小时后失效
Okay. Offer's good for 48 hours.
用说两次"滚出去"吗
Two get out of heres?
你能相信这些小流氓吗
You believe these punks?
他们怎么敢进行那么多目光交流
I mean, what was with all this eye contact?
我那个年代 书呆子会规规矩矩地盯着鞋
In my day, nerds had the decency to stare at their shoes!
他们的网站看起来挺正规的
Their website looks legitimate.
他们还有不少大客户
I mean, they've got some pretty great clients.
等一下 那是玛格丽特吗
Wait a second, is that Margaret?
她在那工作 肯定是他们挖走了她
She's working there. They must have poached her.
他们肯定给她洗脑了
Brainwashed her, is what they did.
玛格丽特很容易上当
Margaret is very vulnerable.
我曾经无数次把她从邪教
I've had to rescue her a bunch of times
和安利金字塔营销中救出来
from cults and an Amway pyramid.
快 去把我们的姑娘救回来
Come on. Let's get our girl back!
你都骑出大峡谷了
You were all the way out of the Grand Canyon
才发现我不在驴上
before you realized no one was on my donkey.
不过 当然 我们去救玛格丽特
But, sure, let's go save Margaret.
妈 我的恐龙派对看起来好棒
Mom, my dinosaur party looks amazing!
可我们订的是那个房间
But we're in that room.
肯定是有人在我们隔壁办了恐龙派对
Somebody must've done another dinosaur party right next to us.
歌洛莉亚
Gloria?
唐娜·邓肯医生
Doctor Donna Duncan.
记得我的继子迪格比吗
You remember my stepson, Digby.
他更喜欢不用语言来交流
He prefers nonverbal communication.
这是你的派对吗
This is your party?
你瞧 我看到你预定
You see, I saw that you had signed up
要给杰西卡老师带的班开派对
to throw a party for Miss Jessica's class,
所以我想给伊莱恩老师带的班也办个小派对
so I thought I'd throw a little party for Miss Elaine.
它能喷完火后朝整个房间喷糖果哦
It belches fire and then shoots candy all over the room.
妹子
Hey, girl, hey!
我不会陪你去公路旅行的
I'm not going on your road trip.
-什么 -卢克告诉我你一直在煽动他
- What? - Luke told me that you've been hounding him
因为你不想独自开车横跨全国
because you don't want to drive cross-country alone.
我只是想帮你个忙
Oh, I'm just trying to do you a favor.
你要去孟斐斯开会
You're going to a conference in Memphis.
我只要多开12小时车程就行了
It's only 12 hours out of my way.
你不必害怕
Hey, no need to be afraid.
害什么怕
Afraid?
曼尼 我是个穿低胸上衣的漂亮女孩
Manny, I'm a pretty girl who wears low-cut tops.
我知道19岁男孩害怕时是什么神情
I know what a scared 19-year-old boy looks like.
老兄 你五年级时带排箫去学校
Dude, you brought a pan flute to the fifth grade.
你给比你人气高超多的女孩唱小夜曲
You serenade girls who are way out of your league.
你胆子很大 你没问题的
You're a baller. You got this.
-多谢鼓励 -随时乐意效劳
- Thanks. - Anytime.
曼尼 曼尼 你这是绑架
Manny. Manny, this is kidnapping.
他们办公室真大
Wow, this office is huge.
刚盖的 这里过去是史怀伯格百货商店
Just placed it. This used to be Schweinberg's department store.
那边是电视墙
Wall of TVs over there.
我当时差点撞翻了芝士火锅样品
I almost knocked down the display of fondue pots
因为我看到他们让芭芭拉·沃尔特斯报新闻
when I saw they were letting Barbara Walters anchor the news.
看看是谁来了
Look who's here!
你们一定不会后悔接受我们的出价
You are not gonna regret taking our offer.
我们去庆祝吧
Let's celebrate.
我们不是来卖公司的
We're not here to sell.
我们是来带玛格丽特回家的
We're here to bring Margaret home.
玛格丽特是谁
Who's Margaret?
玛吉
Margie!
小玛吉
Margie-Marge!
他们怎么骗你来的
How did they get you?
你还独自去宠物店瞎逛吗
Are you still wandering around alone in pet stores?
我告诉过你 这些邪教专拉这种人
I've told you, that's the kind of person these cults target!
我喜欢这里
I like it here.
他们有能做各种汽水的机器
They have one of those machines that makes every kind of soda.
可你有糖尿病 还是个成年人
But you're diabetic. And a grown-up.
既然你们来了 不如我带你们看看新型号
You know, since you're here, why don't I show you the new model?
来 过来
Come here. Come over here.
过来 这是伊瑟拉视界精英
Come here. This is the EzraVision Elitist.
站在这
Stand right over there.
面向前面
Face forward.
下午好 伊瑟拉
Good afternoon, Ezra.
下午好 需要什么帮助吗
Good afternoon. How may I help you?
那是什么
What is that?
伊瑟拉 进行全身扫描
Ezra, full body scan.
-来吧 -扫描完成 搜索衣橱
- Here we go. - Scan complete. Searching wardrobe.
根据今天的天气预报
Based on today's weather forecast,
这是您的最佳着装
here's your optimal outfit.
看看标牌
Check the label.
-正是我的尺寸 -没错
- Just my size. - Yes, it is.
这就是衣柜的未来
See, this is the future of closets --
自动化 智能化
automated, intelligent --
七十年代的"情绪衣柜"也是这么宣传的
That's what they said about the "mood closet" in the '70s,
-我亲手送它入土了 -他真暴躁
- and I buried them. - Very cranky.
是的 不过他赢得了暴躁的权利
Yes, but he has earned the right to be cranky,
因为我父亲是这一行的巨人
because my father is a giant in this industry,
并且他为了来这今天没吃冰淇淋三明治
and he had to skip his ice-cream sandwich today to come here.
尼克 该玩激光枪战了
Nick, it's time for laser tag.
太棒了 你们知道吗
Yes! You know what?
无论最终结果如何 裤子你留着
No matter how it shakes out, you can keep the pants.
-我送你了 -我们走
- Those are on me. - Let's go!
我们快走
Let's get the hell out of here.
等等 爸 我
Hang on, Dad. I...
我和你一样不喜欢这些书呆
I don't like these dorks any more than you do,
但他们有些想法可能很有前景
but they might be onto something.
你什么意思 你想卖公司吗
What are you saying? You want to sell?
不 我在考虑合并
No, I was thinking more of a merger.
我做了些调查
I did some digging,
他们生产不过来 订单排到两年后了
and they are two years behind on production.
他们需要我们的生产能力
They need our manufacturing,
而说实话 我们需要他们的科技
and frankly, we need their technology.
不 不可能 谈话结束
Nope, not gonna happen. End of conversation.
非要这样吗
Really?
我是在跟你讨论公司业务
I-I'm having a business discussion.
不是在商量一个新的睡觉时间
I am not negotiating a new bedtime.
我才不要找一个外人当合伙人
I'm not taking on an outside partner.
我懂了 因为你不太会处理合伙人关系
Oh, I get it, 'cause you're not very good with partners.
你让我当负责人得有九次了吧
I mean, you put me in charge, like, nine times,
但如果是个重要决定
but if it's an important decision,
我就得闭嘴
I should just shut up.
这能怪我吗
Well, I can't help it
我对这行有神一般的第六感
if I have a sixth sense about this business.
是衣柜选择了我
Closets chose me!
我的天啊
Oh, my gosh! Hey!
那边玩得超嗨的
It's going great over there, huh?
怎么回事 这些孩子做错事了吗
What's this? Are these kids in trouble?
那个派对跟这个不一样 高档多了
That's a different, fancier party than this.
这里唯一好玩的就是那个金字塔 材料是...
The only fun thing I have is that pyramid made out of --
小卡 看你那个巨婴外甥干了什么
Ay, Cam, look what your giant baby nephew did!
对 但你要知道 这不是他的错
Yeah, but you know, it's not his fault.
他的身型是同龄孩子的三倍
He's three times the size of a child his age.
还有你知道吗 有些塔克家的孩子
And you know what, some Tucker boys
会很早就经历痛苦的快速成长期
have a young growth spurt that's no picnic.
我小时候得上法院证明年龄才能打少年棒球联盟
I had to go to court to play Little League.
卡梅隆 亲爱的
Cameron, sweetie!
我就觉得听到了你的声音
I thought I heard your voice
穿过这个无趣安静的...
cutting through the joyless silence of this...
我本来想说派对
I want to say party,
但我怕听起来像是讽刺
but I'm afraid it will sound sarcastic.
你们是朋友吗
You guys are friends?
我们在同一家发廊做头发
Uh, well, we go to the same blowout parlor, yeah.
等等 你花钱请我吹头
Wait a minute, did you pay for my Belizian blowout
就是为了让我告诉你歌洛莉亚的派对详情
just so I would shout the details of Gloria's party
好让自己能赢过她吗
so you could outdo her?
你可算明白了
Oh, look at you catching on.
孩子们 很抱歉吵醒你们了
Kids, sorry to wake you.
但我要把这些腕带留在这里
But I'm gonna leave these wristbands here
以防你们想来坐我们的过山车
in case any of you want to come ride our roller coaster.
真正的机械过山车
The mechanical kind,
不是你们走进这里后
not the emotional one you've been on
在心中经历的心情过山车
since you came through these doors.
给我滚出去
Get out of here!
不是你 不是你 不是你
Not you, not you, not you.
天啊 比我想象的还糟糕
Oh, God, this is worse than I thought.
有好多眼睛正盯着我
There are so many eyes on me.
当然了
I mean, yes, sure,
那些独眼巨人让眼睛数目少了点 不过还是多
less because of all the cyclopses, but still.
你可以的 提起你的精[灵]神
You can do this. Elf up.
我最喜欢的两个莱茵少女 琳达 凯伦
My two favorite Rhine maidens! Linda! Karen!
之前卖了她们一套复式公寓
Sold them a duplex.
我了个妈妈咪啊
Sweet home Alduzzarna,
《神剑之战》第五季里的制傻者
it's the Foolmaker from "Clash of Swords" season five!
我只看到了第三季 有点困惑 跟我说说
I'm only on season three. I feel lost. Help me.
好吧 在无花果盛宴上
Oh, okay. During the Feast of Figs,
森林王子把漫游者米苟拉夫驱逐到
the Forest Prince banished Migolaf the Wanderer
遗弃之国境外
to the outer reaches of The Forsaken Realm.
米苟拉夫伏击了依果达然侏儒
Migolaf waylaid the Iguodalan Dwarves
并诅咒那位高级牧师永远痴傻
and cursed the high cleric to an eternity of feeble-mindedness
用的就是这支强大的权杖 它被人称
using the mighty scepter known as...
"制傻者" 我要拍张自拍
The Foolmaker. I got to get a selfie.
小心 小心
Ooh, careful! Careful!
天啊 好吧
Oh, boy. Okay.
还好这不是真货
Good thing it's not the real one
不然我这后半辈子都要受诅咒
or I'd be cursed to spend the rest of my days
变成一个碎碎念的白痴了
as a bumbling idiot.
你要生一个煮粥女仆 还是
Aw, are you gonna have a little porridge maiden
一个小勇士
or a little warrior?
我没怀孕 白痴
I'm not pregnant, dipwad.
菲尔 你为什么这么说
Phil, why would you say that?!
我不知道啊 脱口而出
I don't know, it just came out.
因为这支制傻者...
I mean, The Foolmaker --
你没有被诅咒 好吗 那是道具 不是真的
You're not cursed, okay? It's a prop. It's not real.
好吧 见面座谈会在这边
All right. The panel's this way.
兄弟 你的鳞片铠甲太屌了
Hey, man. Sick scale armor!
真的吗 你真觉得吗 配披风不会太夸张吗
Oh, really? You think so? It's not too much with the cape?
我想要那种既可以赴宴也可以参战的
I wanted something that would go from feast to battle.
-你做到了 -太好了
- Crushed it. - Yes!
我们要拍一张年度北境大合照
Oh, we're about to take our annual Norph group photo.
-你要来吗 -当然
- You coming? -Yes, yes!
菲尔 我们要拍一张照
Phil, we're taking a pic--
抱歉 我跟我朋友走散了
Oh, I'm sorry. I lost my friend.
我们大多数都是一个人来的 没必要假装
Hey, most of us come alone. You don't have to pretend.
我
I -- Th--
太好了 问答环节刚刚开始
Oh, great, the Q&A's just starting.
米奇
Mitch?
这是个非常非常好的问题
That's a very, very good question...
-米奇尔 -问题的答案是
- Mitchell? - ...and the answer to that is...
可怕的食人怪牙齿 你怎么弄来的
Scary ogre teeth. Where'd you get those?
我的亲生父母给的
I'm guessing my birth parents.
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我怎么就不能闭嘴呢
Why can't I just shut up?
抱歉 是我说太久了吗
Sorry, was I going on too long?
我没有
I didn't --
你是乔尔.L.L.罗根
You're Joel L.L. Logan.
你有什么问题 朋友
What's your question, friend?
别害羞
Don't be shy.
虽然的确是我创造了这王国
I may have created this kingdom,
但我们都是这个王国的继承人
but we're all fellow heirs to it.
对吧
Isn't that right?
那样的话 罗根先生
In that case, Mr. Logan...
我在一个粉丝页面上看到
Uh, I read on a fan page
本季季末会出现一个莫兹果人
there's gonna be a Mozgovian uprising in the season finale
消灭所有统治阶级
that'll wipe out the entire ruling class,
包括凶残地斩首正义之子阿德巴约
including the gruesome beheading of Adebayo the Righteous.
等等 你 你要杀死阿德巴约吗
Wait, a-are you -- are you gonna kill Adebayo?
什么 不不不
What? No, no.
谁是 谁 谁是阿德巴约啊
Who's -- Who -- Who's Adebayo?
老天爷啊 看来是真的
Oh, dear lord. It is true.
你个蠢蛋 为什么要问他这个
You fool! Why would you ask him that?!
我们不上剧透网站是有原因的
We all stay off of spoiler sites for a reason!
这是我唯一还在追的剧 你就这么毁了
This show is the only thing I've got going on and you ruined it!
主办单位准你们带晶球入场吗
They let you bring your spheres?!
他们把我的镊子都没收了
They took away my tweezers!
曼尼
Manny?
这是努斯鲍姆太太给的支票
This is the check Mrs. Nussbaum gave me
要我把她的车开到特拉华
to drive her car to Delaware.
如果你跟我走 它就是你的了
It's yours if you come with me.
-好 -等下 什么
- Okay. - Wait, what?
海莉已经警告我你会这么问
Well, Haley already warned me you'd be asking
我想 去就去吧
and I thought, sure.
反正也顺路去我最爱的研究所
My favorite research institute is on the way.
我可以带上我的风向袋和气压表
And I could bring my windsock and barometer
去做我正在进行的天气建模项目
for that new weather modeling project I've been noodling with.
我不禁注意到你枕头上有好多散落的头发
I couldn't help noticing a lot of loose hairs on your pillow
还有一叠做完的数独书
and a stack of fully completed Sudoku books.
你这个夏天不是应该放松吗
Weren't you supposed to be taking it easy this summer?
不考虑学习 项目
No school, no projects --
对 我特喜欢这生活
Yeah, I'm loving it.
那我打开你的衣柜
What are the chances I open your dresser
会不会找到一本日历 上面有三天打叉
and find a calendar with three X'd out days
开学的日期上有大大的红色的圈
and a giant red circle around the date school starts again?
你不了解我
You don't know me.
你正在面临你所畏惧的挑战
Look, you're facing a challenge that scares you,
但你内心也知道你需要正面迎敌
but you know in your heart you need to take it on.
因为它能帮助你成长
Because it'll help you grow
成为一个更强大 生活更平衡的人
and become a stronger, more balanced person.
我当然知道你是对的 但很难
Of course I know you're right, but it's hard!
有人在外面探索星球
People are out there discovering planets,
我却在家做网上的白痴小测验
and I'm in here doing BuzzFeed quizzes.
如果我是披头士的一员 我会是谁
Like if I were to be a Beatle, who would I be?
我会是林戈 谁在乎呢 曼尼
I'd be Ringo. Who cares, Manny?!
曼尼
Manny?
我可能丢失了菲尔 但找到了我的同类
I may have lost Phil, but I found my people.
舞蹈轻而易举
And the choreography was a snap.
基本上就是大河之舞穿插着霍拉舞
It's basically a river dance, uh, crossed with the hora.
我从卡塔丽娜之间带回了消息
I bring news from the Catalina Room!
黑影笼罩了这个帝国
A dark shadow has fallen upon the kingdom.
神明会因此而动怒
The gods will not be pleased by this --
快说 盖里
Just get to it, Gary!
有个家伙剧透了季终集
Some dingus just spoiled the finale!
必须惩罚他
This shall not go unpunished!
咱们找他去
Let's get him!
你去哪了 我等了好久
Where have you been? I've been waiting forever.
我很生气 我需要走一走
I was angry. I needed to take a walk
这样才能忘了你有多固执
so I could forget how pigheaded you can be.
你想再走一圈吗
You want to take another lap?
爸 我是对的
Dad, I am right about this.
总有一天尼克能想出怎么保证供货
Eventually Nick is gonna figure out how to keep up with demand,
那到时候我们该何去何从
and then where are we gonna be?
我知道你的风格是坚持到底
I know your style has always been just tough it out
击退每一个威胁
and -- and beat back every threat --
不是 克莱尔
That's not it, Claire.
你是对的 我们打不过他们
You're right. We can't beat these guys.
从长远看合并才是唯一可行的办法
A merger's the only long-term play.
我只是不知道该把自己放在什么位置
I just don't know who I am in there.
什么
What?
他们都25岁左右 飞驰在那什么上
They're all 25, zippin' around on their...
平衡车吗
The hoverboards?
那我成了什么 可爱的老家伙
What's that make me, the cute old guy?
还是吉祥物
The mascot?
"老普里契特在厕所呢
"Old man Pritchett's in the men's room.
快去看他又对着自动水龙头乱骂"
Let's go watch him cuss out the automatic faucets again."
爸
Aw, Dad.
我不能保证
I can't promise that
你在那栋楼里不会感到自己老了
you wouldn't feel old in that building,
但从外面看来
but from the outside looking in,
你完全镇得住
I mean, you're the guy
一群年纪只有自己三分之一的小屁孩
who's holding his own with kids a third his age.
你就好比是衣柜界的托尼·班尼特
That makes you like the... the Tony Bennett of closets.
我和你说过我曾在罗马和他坐同班电梯吧
I told you I took an elevator with him in Rome, right?
你说过 你知道吗
Yeah, you did. And you know what,
那栋楼里有好多人
in that building there's a bunch of people
还没听过这个故事呢
who have never heard that story.
他是不是还带了只吉娃娃
Did he have a Chihuahua with him?
-貂 -貂
- A mink. - A mink?
-一只活貂 -没错
- A live mink. - Yeah.
-可有范儿了 -没错
- All class. - Yeah.
可能我觉得有点受威胁吧
It's just a little intimidating.
你觉得他们不会怕你吗
You don't think they're gonna be scared of you?
别啊 爸 你看他们
Come on. Dad, look at them.
无论他们的衣柜帮他们挑出了什么毒舌T恤
I don't care what ironic T-shirt their closets pick out for them.
他们本质上始终还是死书呆
Underneath, they're still nerds.
真是服了你
I can't.
是啦 我想我应该能行吧
Yeah, this might be okay.
我想见他 让我过去 让我过去
I want to see him. Let me through, let me through!
你就是剧透的家伙吗
You're the spoiler?
我不是故意的
I didn't do it on purpose!
是制傻者害的
It was The Foolmaker!
权杖只是个道具好吗
The scepter is a prop, okay?
你是自己被心里暗示所影响了
It's just the power of suggestion.
米奇尔 他们想收走我的全通票
Mitchell, they want to take away my all-access pass.
-你得帮我 -你认识这个败类吗
- You've got to help me. - You know this scoundrel?
算吧 我们两家的孩子好像在同学校...
Uh, yeah, I think our kids go to school with one --
-米奇尔 -好吧 我认识他
- Mitchell! ?- Okay yes, yes -- yes, I know him.
-我认识他 -他们是恶魔
- I know him! - They're monsters.
他们一直朝我丢乔巴尼连枷球
They've been pelting me with Chobani flail spheres.
等下 乔巴尼 那个酸奶品牌吗
Wait -- Ch-Chobani, like the yoghurt?
剧在第四季时接了商业植入
The show took on corporate sponsors in season four.
不是吧 盖里
Seriously, Gary?
我帮忙你组建了牌组呢
I helped you build a deck!
停 停 我们在做什么
Okay, stop, stop it! What are we doing, huh?
北境人是这样的吗
Is this how Norphs behave?
其实我们还挺好战的
Actually, we're quite war-like.
看 看 这个人他犯了错
Look, look, this man, he made a mistake,
但如果我们驱逐他
but if we banish him,
我们就和这些年来羞辱咱们的人一样了
we're no better than the people who shamed us all these years,
他们在团队运动时最后选咱们
who -- who picked us last for team sports,
群发律师协会舞会邀请邮件时漏掉咱们
who left us off of group e-mails about bar association dances.
我们是怪咖 奇葩 怪胎
We're all oddballs and misfits and weirdos,
但这里最好的地方就是包容一切
but the great thing about this place is we all belong,
特别是这个善良的人
especially this good man,
是他给了我战胜恐惧的勇气
who gave me the courage to conquer my fear
让我成为这个团体的一部分
and become part of this community.
让我们欢迎他回来
Let's welcome him back.
红色的 盖里
The red one, Gary!
那个恐龙在哪
Where is that dinosaur?
我十分希望我没有
I certainly hope I don't
一不小心关了灯
accidentally turn off the lights.
身为一名同性恋 我认识市里所有派对策划人
As a gay man, I know every party planner in town.
所以我发了条群短信 我也真撞了大运
So I sent out a group text, and as luck would have it,
我朋友罗纳多刚好结束一场儿童的小飞侠派对
my friend Ronaldo was wrapping up a kid's Peter Pan party.
我就说"你的派对有什么都带过来吧"
And I said, "Send me whatever you got."
我好像听到音乐啦
I think I hear some music!
失踪的小男孩们都在哪啊
Where my lost boys at?!
这是什么鬼啊
What the hell is this?!
你不是说你在一场儿童的小飞侠派对吗
You said you were at a kid's Peter Pan party?
不是不是 我是说"尔铜的小飞侠派对"
No, no, no. I said, "Kit's Peter Pan party."
尔铜叔第11次办50岁大寿了
It's his 11th time turning 50.
大家闭上眼睛 别看
Close your eyes! No! Don't look at that!
拜托了 大家对不起
Please, I'm so sorry!
够了 够了
Enough! Enough!
大家都出去 小孩子们也出去
Everybody out! Even the kids!
我坚持不下去了 你们去有趣派对那边吧
I can't fight this anymore. Go to the nice party!
跟着仙女娘娘过去吧
Just follow the fairy!
她是说我 不是大家娘 冷静
She meant me. Everybody calm down.
今天谢谢你了
Thank you so much for today.
要我自己肯定坚持不下去
I-I never would've gone through with it
都多亏了你的鼓舞
if you hadn't inspired me.
我鼓舞了你吗
I inspired you?
等等
Wait.
在第三册中 高等祭司
In book the third, the high cleric
成功克服制傻者的诅咒
overcomes the curse of the Foolmaker
靠的就是纯真之心
by being pure of heart
之后他成为了伟大的人民鼓舞者
and goes on to be a great inspirer of people.
你觉得...
Do you think --
你看起来好阴郁
You seem glum.
或许你该把你的热忱放在别的方向
Perhaps you should be turning your passions elsewhere.
你说得对 我要回去读兽医
You're right. I'm going back to vet school.
我也该长大了
It's about time I grew up.
我对不起你 歌洛莉亚
I'm sorry, Gloria.
没事啦 我不生气
It's okay. I'm not mad.
派对怎么没了
What happened to the party?
被小卡给毁了
Cam ruined it two ways.
我只是想帮乔办一个好的派对
I just wanted a nice party for Joe.
能帮孩子把一切做到尽善尽美的日子很短
There's only so long that you can make things perfect for them.
突然有天 他们就要离巢
Suddenly, they move on.
他们某天早上起来
They wake up one morning
就说要独自开车横跨全国
and they want to drive cross-country all alone.
对 曼尼
Oh, right, Manny.
我知道你在害怕 但你应该感到自豪啊
I know you're scared, but your should feel proud.
你把一个...
You took kind of a...
你可以直说 一个小怪胎
You can say it -- a weird kid.
一个小怪胎养育成了一个
A weird kid, and turned him into somebody
对自己感到自信果敢
so comfortable with himself
愿意去开启一段挺大冒险的男子汉
that he's willing to take on a pretty big adventure.
谢谢你 小卡
Thank you, Cam.
我也想有这样的教育
I wish I had that.
我小时候也是个小怪胎
I mean, I was a weird kid
但我的家庭只让我觉得自己更怪了
whose family only made him feel weirder.
我一直到今天才有这份自信与勇气
I mean, it took until today to do an adventure
做到我在曼尼那个年纪就想去做的冒险
that I have wanted to do since I was Manny's age.
我去了英雄展
I-I went to Hero-Con.
没穿戏服吧
Not in costume?
穿了 菲茨宝
Affirmative, Fizbo.
好吧 那如果你喜欢这些
Okay, if this is something you're into,
你为什么从不跟我说呢
why haven't you ever told me?
我从没跟任何人说过
I haven't told anyone.
我试过跟我妈说过一次
I mean, I tried with my mom once,
但我临阵怂了 最后跟她说我是同性恋
but I chickened out and told her I was gay instead.
那会儿我自己都还没确定性向呢
And I-I wasn't even sure at that point.
为什么有这么多家长可以教育错孩子的方式啊
Why are there so many ways for a parent to break a kid?
-抱抱 -不 别 别啊
- Hug! - No, no, no!
这让我好担心这个小伙子啊
Aw, you know, it makes me worried for this little guy.
我爱我的爸妈
I love my parents,
但是他们当年也不太会教...
but they weren't exactly the best when I was...
还这么大时的我
when I was this.
去玩吧
Go play.
米奇尔 我为你今天勇敢追梦
Mitchell, I'm, uh, proud of the risk you took today
感到十分骄傲
following your heart.
你应该多多这样
You should do more of that.
小卡 我们该收留卡尔吗
Cam, should Cal live with us?
应该
He should.
很好
Very well.
抱歉我们迟到了 堵车嘛
Sorry we're late. Traffic, you know.
我一直叫你用防堵车导航软件
I keep telling you to try Waze,
可你害怕使用新科技 其实你不该怕啊
but you're scared of technology, and you shouldn't be.
我们要将普里契特衣柜跟高科技公司合并
We're merging Pritchett's with a high-tech closet company.
太棒了
Excellent.
歌洛莉亚 你常提到你对腹语术很有兴趣
And, Gloria, you speak often of your passion for ventriloquism.
菲尔 今天已经够累了
It's been a long day, Phil.
这一个需要多一点时间
This one needs more time.
旅途随笔
Notes from the road.
又名《我心中的美国》
Alternate title, The United States of me.
恐惧 是敌还是友
Fear -- Friend or Foe?
在小时候 我们被教要恐惧能伤我们的事物
As children, we're taught to fear what can hurt us.
但成年之后 我们却被要求能克服恐惧
But as adults, we're expected to conquer what we're afraid of.
所以什么是恐惧呢
So what are fears?
恐惧是让我们生存
Do they keep us alive?
还是让我们无法享受生活
Or do they keep us from living?
你把车道堵住了 赶紧开车走人吧
You're blocking the driveway. Hit the road already.
好啦 我这就出发
Okay, I'm going.
杰
Jay.
快点啦
Hurry up.
我们想回家了
We want to go home.
这破玩意他妈就是不灵啊
I can't get this damn thing to work.
惨了 是那种自动感应洗手台
Oh no, it's one of those automatic sinks.
我觉得吧 你应该来个强行重启
You know what? You should do a hard reboot.
先走回小便斗再重新走近洗手台
Go back to the urinal and reapproach.
里面发生什么事了
What's going on in there?
这玩意半滴都流不出来
I can't even get a trickle out of this thing!
不去想就尿得出了
I find not thinking about it helps.
他是说水龙头
It's the sink.
根本没道理 我都已经挥舞手臂
It makes no sensethat I'm waving my arms
挥得像在指挥飞机对接舱门那么夸张了
like I'm directing a plane into a gate!
他会把它砸了
He's gonna break it,
就像他把遥控器砸了一样
like he broke the remote control.
真是... 那个纸巾架也是自动感应的
This is... the paper towel thing is automatic too.
老爸
Oh, dad.